<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Theoretically Josh</title><link>https://theoreticallyjosh.com/</link><description>Recent content on Theoretically Josh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>jlhags+blog@gmail.com (Joshua Hagofsky)</managingEditor><webMaster>jlhags+blog@gmail.com (Joshua Hagofsky)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 09:15:05 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theoreticallyjosh.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beginning Programming Lesson 01</title><link>https://theoreticallyjosh.com/post/beginning-programming-lesson-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 09:15:05 -0700</pubDate><author>jlhags+blog@gmail.com (Joshua Hagofsky)</author><guid>https://theoreticallyjosh.com/post/beginning-programming-lesson-01/</guid><description>When I was about 12 years old, my aunt gave us an old computer. Without going into all the details, I broke it, and all that it would then let you do is write programs in BASIC. It came with a book explaining how to do various things with the language. So having nothing better to do, I worked through it and taught myself how to code, and eventually went to college to learn how to do it better.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://theoreticallyjosh.com/page/privacy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 10:18:36 -0700</pubDate><author>jlhags+blog@gmail.com (Joshua Hagofsky)</author><guid>https://theoreticallyjosh.com/page/privacy/</guid><description>Privacy Policy for Theoretically Josh At Theoretically Josh, accessible from https://theoreticallyjosh.com, one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by Theoretically Josh and how we use it.
If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us.
This Privacy Policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website with regards to the information that they shared and/or collect in Theoretically Josh.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to the Command Line</title><link>https://theoreticallyjosh.com/post/introduction-to-the-commandline/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 11:05:10 -0700</pubDate><author>jlhags+blog@gmail.com (Joshua Hagofsky)</author><guid>https://theoreticallyjosh.com/post/introduction-to-the-commandline/</guid><description>The command line can feel a bit like a step backwards in terms of user experience, or even intimidating. However, it can be a very powerful tool, and even impossible to avoid if you want to program or be involved in IT.
What is it? Probably the most recognizable image of the command line is that black box on the screen with green text. Basically it is a place to interact with your computer via text rather than photos (mostly).</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://theoreticallyjosh.com/page/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 10:22:33 -0700</pubDate><author>jlhags+blog@gmail.com (Joshua Hagofsky)</author><guid>https://theoreticallyjosh.com/page/about/</guid><description>My name is Joshua (Josh) Hagofsky. I began programming when I was 12 years old. My family didn&amp;rsquo;t have much money. So, the only computer we had was an old Commodore 64 that our aunt gave us. I somehow managed to fry the serial port, which meant no external storage would work. The only thing I could do with it was program in BASIC. Luckily, it came with a book on how to do just that.</description></item></channel></rss>